# JESSE TUREK

eCommerce Professional Software Engineer

Brooklyn, NY, 11238

github.com/turekjesse

in linkedin.com/in/turekjesse

turekjesse@gmail.com

(609) 947-1416

jesseturek.netlify.app

### CAREER SUMMARY

I am a Brooklyn-Based Web-Developer with 5 years of prior experience in eCommerce and a life-long passion for building, fixing, and tinkering with things. My knack for mechanics paired with my meticulous attention to detail and creative problem solving skills were the driving forces that lead me to learn to code.

## **SKILLS**









































PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE



Software Engineering Fellow

General Assembly

May 2021 - August 2021

- Learned programming and computer science fundamentals, as well as software engineering best practices in regards to full-stack development
- Worked collaboratively in an Agile development workflow using indusry-standard version control tools to build full-stack applications

## carbartt

Content Manager

Carhartt Work in Progress

March 2018 - May 2021

- Defined internal digital asset management workflows, best practices, and organizational structure using Dropbox Business
- Executed weekly site-wide content updates to align with sale performance, on-hand inventory, and marketing initiatives
- Coordinated with various internal teams to compile and maintain product data for 1000+ SKUs seasonally
- Bridged connections between various systems to accurately display essential product assets on us.carhartt-wip.com
- Designed and Built custom email marketing campaigns using Sketch and Mailchimp ESP
- Liaised with external agencies to implement site enhancements in an agile workflow
- Participated in the review and testing of new developments, designs, and features
- Reported weekly KPI's in regards to site user-behavior and email marketing campaigns

Ecommerce Manager

Unis New York

November 2015 - December 2017

- Merged independent sales channels and inventory into one omni-channel platform (Shopify)
- Spearheaded complete web and mobile redesign of www.unisnewyork.com while meeting budget and deadline
- Achieved a 37% increase in revenue and a 17% increase in conversion from 2016 to 2017
- Streamlined end-to-end product launch and site merchandising process to offset production delays
- Reduced yearly operational costs by \$31,000

EASTERN MANNER Co-Creator

Passion Project

June 2010 - October 2017

Eastern Manner was conceived in 2010 as a creative outlet to test my woodworking and engineering skills, and ultimately attempt to bring something new to the skateboard industry. As Eastern Manner evolved into small business, my interest in the digital world grew and sent me down a path that led to a career focused in Ecommerce, Digital Marketing, and Technology.

## **EDUCATION**